A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Education and Public Policy Program (EPP), Resources and the Environment, Program Staff Files FA641
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Education and Public Policy Program (EPP), Resources and the Environment, Program Staff Files
1963-1980
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA641
5.24 Cubic Feet
Separated Materials
Appendix A: Reports – Unpublished reports written by Ford Foundation staff and consultants were removed from their original folders, scanned and transferred to the Archives' collection of staff and consultant reports. See Appendix A for a list of these reports and their specific assigned number. The reports are listed in alphabetical order by author. The assigned number may be used to access reports in the online catalog.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Arrangement
Arranged into 3 series:
I. Subject Files.
II. Resource and Environment Diary.
III. Chronological Correspondence Files.
Conditions Governing Access
Records more than 10 years old are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Scope and Contents
Contains correspondence, reports, papers, consultants files and program records.
- Subject Files, 1963-1980; I
  - Resources and Environment Study" -- Discussion Paper, 1963 December (Box 1)
  - Resources and Environment Study -- Final Report and Recommendations, 1964 April (Box 1)
  - Conference on Natural Resources -- Discussion Papers (1/2), 1964 February 27-March 1 (Box 1)
  - Conference on Natural Resources -- Discussion Papers (2/2) (second copy), 1964 February 27-March 1 (Box 1)
  - "Land Acquisition" -- Discussion Paper, 1964 December (Box 1)
  - "Critical Needs in Land Use and Preservation: A Suggested Role for the Ford Foundation" -- Report of Advisory Committee on Land Use and Preservation, 1966 September 15 (Box 1)
  - Response to Environmental and Resource Problems -- Report of the Seminar on the Uses of Ecology (Ford Foundation), 1967 January 26-27 (Box 1)
  - Conservation Foundation, Inc. -- Committee for Economic Development -- RGA, Press Release, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Energy Grants, Fiscal Years 1974-1978, circa 1978 (Box 1)
  - Energy Grants -- RFF; Environmental Action Foundation; Rand Corporation; Brookings Institution, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Environmental Defense Fund, Inc. -- RGAs, 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - Ford Foundation -- Personnel Policies -- Travel and Expenses Handbook, 1977 (Box 1)
  - India Trip File -- Energy Related Materials, 1979 (Box 1)
  - "Energy: The Next Twenty Years" -- Study Group Members and Energy Report and Reviews, 1978 (Box 1)
  - "Energy: The Next Twenty Years", 1979 (Box 1)
  - Energy Books -- Reviews of "Energy: The Next Twenty Years"; "Energy in America's Future"; "Energy Future", 1980 (Box 1)
  - Energy Consultants Meeting File (incl. May 13, 1980 meeting) (Box 1)
  - (The) Energy Policy Project, 1975-1977 (Box 1)
  - Gravel, Mike (Alaska senator) -- Government Stock Ownership Corporation (GSOC), 1977-1979 (Box 1)
  - Nuclear Energy Policy Study Group -- Members, 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - Nuclear Energy Policy Study -- Correspondence, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Program Plans, Energy Studies Grants, etc., 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Consultant -- Gordon Harrison, 1978 October 1-1979 April 15 (Box 1)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Consultant -- Gordon Harrison -- General Correspondence Re: Workshops, Papers, etc., 1974-1976 (Box 1)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Consultant -- Vernon W. Ruttan, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Resources for the Future -- Re: Energy Projects (including ARDEN), 1979-1980 (Box 2)
  - Resources for the Future -- Ford Foundation Grant, 1979 (Box 2)
  - "Saving Energy: An Idea for a Private-Sector Initiative" by M. Sviridoff, 1979 (Box 2)
  - "Science in this Foundation" Memo by Marshall Robinson and Related Science Memoranda, 1977 (Box 2)
  - Scientists' Institute for Public Information (SIPI) -- Meetings and Conferences, 1979 (Box 2)
  - Shareholders Resolution -- Pacific Gas and Electric Co., 1980 (Box 2)
  - Staff -- Memoranda (to and from) Re: Ford Foundation Administrative Policies, Staff Appointments, etc., 1977-1980 (Box 2)
  - State Environmental Management Program, 1977 (Box 2)
  - Status Reports -- Education and Public Policy Division (grants lists), 1980 (Box 2)
  - Thomas, Franklin A. -- Memos Re: Various Subjects Incl. Resources and the Environment and Education and Public Policy Grants, Proposals, 1979-1980 (Box 2)
  - Trustee Committee Paper -- Resources and the Environment Program, 1979 December (Box 2)
  - UNESCO MINESPOL II Conference (Belgrade, Yugoslavia), 1979 September 11-16 (Box 2)
  - Urban Impact Statements, undated (Box 2)
- Resource and Environment Diary, 1967-1974; II
  - Resources and the Environment -- Diary of Activities, 1967 February-1968 December (Box 2)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Diary of Activities, 1969 January-1971 December (Box 2)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Diary of Activities, 1972 January-1973 November (Box 2)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Diary of Activities, 1974 January-April (Box 2)
- Chronological Correspondence Files, 1963-1973; III
  - Gordon Harrison -- Chronological Correspondence, 1963 April-December (Box 3)
  - Gordon Harrison -- Chronological Correspondence, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, 1965 January-June (Box 3)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, 1965 July-December (Box 3)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, 1966 January-June (Box 3)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, 1966 July-December (Box 3)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, 1967 January-March (Box 3)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, 1967 April (Box 3)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, 1967 May-June (Box 3)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, 1970 July-August (Box 3)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, 1970 September-December (Box 3)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, 1971 April (Box 3)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, 1971 May (Box 3)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, 1971 June (Box 3)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, 1971 August (Box 3)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, 1971 September-October (Box 3)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, 1971 November-December (Box 3)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, 1972 January (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, 1972 February (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, 1972 March (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, 1972 April (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, 1972 May (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, 1972 June (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, 1972 July (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, 1972 August (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, 1972 September (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, 1972 October (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, 1972 November (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, 1972 December (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, 1973 January (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, 1973 February (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, 1973 March (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, 1973 April (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, 1973 May (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, 1973 June (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, 1973 July (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, 1973 August (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, 1973 September (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, 1973 October (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, 1973 November (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, 1973 December (Box 4)